杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们接下来要做的是,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: What
we want to do next,
现在我们有了我们的网站，它显示图片，我们有了一些内容。
now that we've got our site, it's showing
pictures, we've got some content.
但是我们想要添加更多，对吗？
But we want to add more, right?
我想在这里得到食谱。
I want to get recipes on here.
我希望能够找到不同的方式来重复 Negroni。
I want to be able to check out
different ways to riff on the Negroni.
为了做到这一点，我们将使用我们的文档名称
And to do that we're going
to use our docs name
因为食谱是一种记录形式。
because recipes are a form
of documentation.
那么，让我们把方木桩的一些角削掉，把它放进圆孔里。
So let's, we'll shave some corners of that
square peg and get it into the round hole.
我们要做的就是从安装开始。
So the way that we're gonna do that is we
will go ahead and start by installing it.
所以我们要去纱工作空间内格罗尼斯添加。
So we're gonna yarn
workspace negronis add.
然后我们要引用它，因为我们正在安装一个工作空间主题。
And then we're gonna quote it since
we're installing a work space theme.
盖茨比-主题-文档@明星，一旦我们得到这个,
Gatsby-theme-docs@ star and
once we get this in,
我们将进入配置，我们要安装它与一些选项。
we'll get into the config and
we're gonna install it with some options.
所以，首先，我们将解决盖茨比主题的文档和
So first,
we'll resolve gatsby-themed-docs and
在选项中，我想改变基本路径为食谱和
in the options I want to change
the base path to be recipes and
我也想设置的内容路径，因为我已经有一些食谱定义在这里。
I also want to set the content path cuz I
already have some recipes defined in here.
所以它们在内容食谱中
So they're in content recipes so
我们将其设置为内容路径，内容食谱，好吗？
we'll set that to be the content path,
content recipes okay?
一旦配置好了，我们就可以做一些事情了。
Once this is configured,
then we can do a couple things.
所以第一件事就像我说的,
So the first thing is just
like in the honck if I say,
我们想把布局从我们的网站上撤下来，用在文档的名字里。
we wanna pull the layout out of our
site and use it in the docs name.
所以我要创建盖茨比主题码头
So I'm going to create
Gatsby theme docks and
然后我将进入组件，我们将创建一个 layout.js。
then I'm going to get into
components we'll create a layout.js.
我要导入布局
And I'm gonna import Layout
从组件 / 布局。
from components/Layout.
然后导出默认值，Jason Lengstorf: Layout。
And then export default,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Layout.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 然后，让我们来看看，看看会发生什么。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And then, let's
just take a look and see how that goes.
因此，我们将开发纱线工作空间内格罗尼。
So we'll do yarn workspace
negronis develop.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 一旦我们开始，我们应该看到的是我们已经得到了
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And once we get this
started, what we should see is we've got
这里有四个食谱，其中一个在 index.MDX，这意味着,
four recipes in here and
one of them is at index.MDX, which means,
根据我们的配置，我应该能够访问 / 食谱。
according to our config,
I should be able to visit /recipes.
让我们来看看。
So let's take a look.
好的，很好，这很好。
Okay, all right, this is good.
所以我们可以从一开始就看到一些问题。
So we can see a couple issues
right out of the gate.
第一，这种颜色不适合我们。
So one, is that this is not the right
color that's not going to work for us.
所以几乎没有足够的对比度来清晰可读。
So there's not nearly enough contrast for
that to be legible.
这也没什么意义。
And then this doesn't
really make sense either.
所以我们想改变这段文字。
So we want to change out that text.
所以我故意把这个组件设计得很糟糕，因为
And so I actually purposely designed
this component poorly, because what
你可以添加一个 Props 或者你可以解析不同的文本,
you could do is you could add a Props or
you could parse in different text,
你可以把标题和目录本身分开。
you could separate the heading
from the table of contents itself.
但是我只想展示一种快速覆盖某些组件的方法。
But I wanted to show just a quick
way to override some components.
我们要做的就是进入我们的主题
So what we're gonna do
is go into our theme and
我去拿这个目录我去复印整个东西。
I'm just gonna grab this table-of-contents
I'm gonna copy the whole thing.
然后我会回来，看看盖茨比主题文档的组成部分。
And then I'm gonna come back down,
go into Gatsby theme docs components.
我要创建一个目录气体。
And I'm gonna create
a table of contents gas.
我可以把它粘贴进去。
And I can paste it in.
然后我会把它改成所有的食谱。
And then I'm going to change
it to say all recipes.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 这就是我需要改变的。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
that's all I need to change.
所以，如果我停止并重新启动这个 Jason Lengstorf: 无论何时
So, if I stop and restart this
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Whenever
你跟踪一个组件，你必须停下来重新启动才能让盖茨比把它捡起来,
you shadow a component, you have to stop
and restart to get Gatsby to pick that up,
这就是为什么我们不停地开关它。
so that's why we're turning it on and
off again.
现在基本上我只是复制粘贴到了那个组件做了一个快速的改变
And now basically I just copy pasted the
got to that component made a quick change
他们的方法来更好地抽象它。
their ways to abstract it better.
有一些方法可以让我们通过我们所在的数据层进行配置
There are ways to make that configurable
through the data layer where we were
也许从数据层中提取一个选项作为标题。
maybe pulling like an option out of the
data layer and using that as the title.
但这就像是。
But this is like the.
最直接的方法就是按照制造任何东西的原理来取零件
The most straightforward way is just take
the component exactly as is make whatever
但是值得注意的是，我们现在拒绝了如果事情改变上游,
changes but it's worth noting, we've
now rejected if things change upstream,
我们需要把这些变化迁移回去。
we would need to go and get those
changes and migrate them back in.
所以解决这个问题最有效的方法就是复制粘贴
So this is the heaviest way of solving
this problem is a full copy paste
然后，我们来看一下,
of the component
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Then,
现在我们把这个放在这里,
now that we've got this in here,
另一件事，我想做的是我想添加一个链接到它的主页。
the other thing that I wanna do is I want
to add a link to it on the homepage.
让我们来看看这个主页。
So let's go to this homepage.
我已经把我们的历史记录下来了。
And I've got our history here.
我要把这个改成食谱,
I'm gonna change this over to be recipes,
然后我们会说看菜谱。
and we'll say see recipes.
好的，我在这里看到了一些问题，第一个是我们的按钮被打碎了
Okay, so I see a couple issues here, the
first one is our buttons are smashes into
所以我们可以轻松解决这个问题。
each other, so we can solve that easily.
我们只需要加一点左边距，好的，酷,
We'll just add a little bit of
left hand margin, okay cool,
这个问题已经解决了，但是我想在这里加入视觉层次。
that problem's solve, but
I want to add visual hierarchy here.
我希望人们能看到这些食谱。
I want the recipes to be
the thing that people look at.
所以我希望这是一个主要的突出按钮。
So I want that to be kind of
a primary standout button.
为了做到这一点，我要加入一个不同的变体，叫做 primary。
So to do that, I'm gonna add
a different variant called primary.
我可以进入我的盖茨比插件主题 UI。
And I can get into my
Gatsby plugin theme UI.
我要做的是
And what I'm gonna do for
为了经验起见，我要复制一下。
the sake of experience here is
I'm going to just duplicate it.
但是很多情况都不会改变。
But a lot of these setting
aren't gonna change.
所以，在你的应用程序中，你可能需要抽象出一些常见的东西
So, in your app you'll probably
want to abstract out common
纽扣的东西，就像一个普通的按钮，对象，但
button stuff in like a common button,
object, but
我不想让大家看到我重构一个对象
I don't wanna make everybody
watch me refactor an object, so
你要知道，这可能是你想做的事。
just know that that's probably
something you would wanna do.
那么，让我们看看，我们希望这是主要的
So then, let's see,
we want that to be the primary and
我们把这个设置成背景。
we'll set this to be the background.
然后我认为我们只是想像，当我们聚焦将使用辅助颜色和
And then I think we just want like, when
we focus will use the secondary color and
当我们盘旋将使用辅助颜色。
when we hover will use
the secondary color.
我想这就是我们需要改变的。
And I think that's gonna
be all we need to change.
让我们来看看。
So let's take a look.
是的，这就够了，不是吗？
Yeah, that's good enough, right?
所以这仍然是可见的。
So that's still visible.
很明显，它比历史记录按钮更有视觉冲击力
It's clearly kind of got more visual
weight than the history button, and
可以带我们通过。
that will take us through.
所以让我们来修正这个暗淡的颜色，让它看起来更明显一些。
So let's fix this muted color,
make that a little more visible.
所以，为了做到这一点，我可以在这里，我们将做颜色。
So, to do that,
I can just go in here we'll do colors.
我们可以解决这样一个低破折号合并以及。
We could solve this with like
a low dash merge as well.
让这个看起来不那么恶心，但我觉得现在还可以。
To make this a little less gross,
but I think it's okay for now.
那么我们就这么做，比如说555，怎么样？
So we'll just do,
let's say 555, how's that work?
这样好多了。
That's much better.
所以现在我们有点覆盖了它。
So now we've kind of overwritten this.
我们已经让我们的文字更清晰了，我们有了一个正常运行的网站,
We've made our text a little more legible,
we've got a functioning site,
你永远不会知道，这本来是用来记录的。
and you'd never know that this was
originally intended to be documentation.
它只是按照我们放在这里的食谱的风格工作。
It just works with the style of
recipe that we've put in here.
这真的很不错，对吧？
So this is really nice, right?
我们已经安装了主题，并且已经开始运行
We've got the theme installed,
and up and running, and
定制，只需要几个文件，对我们的风格进行一些调整。
customized, in just a few files,
a couple tweaks to our styles.